Itamar Franco Salazar Reque

🛮 (+51) 991809358 | 🔀 itamarf.salazar@gmail.com | 🛅 itamarsalazar

Summary_

In my undergraduate thesis I studied algorithms to automatically detect ill areas over leaf digital images, this study allowed me to have a better understanding of some machine learning techniques (SVM, ANN, KNN, among others) and to have a better sense about the difficulty of vision tasks. After that I attended some short courses about neuroscience and I have become interested in the field and in the brain. I made a master in which I explored some techniques to solve the EEG inverse problem (MNE, WMNE, FOCUSS, MFOCUSS and Multiple Sparse Priors), I manipulated EEG recordings taken during attention tasks (P300 waves) using SPM software. During the last year I have been using CNNs in different problems like image or video classifications. I observed that current AI techniques have some problems manipulating "the unknown" in classification tasks (a.k.a openset problem) and that are vulnerable to small changes (adversarial examples). I am interested on those problems.

Education

Universidad Nacional de Ingeniería

Lima, Perú

MASTER OF SCIENCE, ELECTRONIC ENGINEER

• Performance of EEG inverse techniques when varying electrode numbers and noise.

Universidad Nacional de Ingeniería

Lima, Perú

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, TELECOMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

- Algorithms for leaf ill areas segmentation on digital images.
- Placed first in graduating class

Experience

INICTEL-UNI Lima, Perú

2015 - Present RESEARCHER

- · App to identify avocado diseases from digital images.
- Satellite image processing to calculate evapotranspiration.

Universidad Tecnológica del Perú (UTP)

Lima, Perú

TEACHING

06/2019 - Present

- Neural networks and fuzzy logic
- · Digital Image Processing

Universidad Nacional Tecnológica de Lima Sur (UNTELS)

Lima, Perú

03/2019 - 06/2019

- · Digital Signal Processing
- Signals and Systems
- · Numerical Methods
- · Programming Language

New York Institute of Technology

New York, U.S.A Oct. 2017 - Dec. 2017

VISITING RESEARCH FELLOW

· Algorithms to process functional imaging of olfactory bulb responses

Contributions

Salazar-Reque, I.F., Huaman, S. (Accepted) Automatic Leaf Segmentation from Images Taken Under

Uncontrolled Conditions Using Convolutional Neural Networks. In: Brazilian Technology Symposium'19 – [1] Perú 2019 (BTSym 2019)

Conference

- Morales, G., Salazar-Reque, I.F., Telles, J., Díaz, D. Detecting Violent Robberies in CCTV Videos Using Deep
- [2] Learning. In: 15th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence Applications and Innovations (AIAI 2019), **DOI:** 10.1007/978-3-030-19826-7

Conference

- Salazar-Reque, I.F., Pacheco, A.G., Rodriguez, R.Y., Lezama, J., and Huaman, S. An image processing
- method to automatically identify Avocado leaf state. In: XXII Symposium on Image, Signal Processing and [3] Artificial Vision (STSIVA 2019). DOI: 10.1109/STSIVA.2019.8730218

Conference

Salazar-Reque, I.F., Kemper G., Huamán S. G. H., Telles J. and Diaz D., (2019). An Algorithm for Plant Disease

Visual Symptom Detection in Digital Images based on Superpixels. International Journal on Advanced [4] Science, Engineering and Information Technology, 9(1), pp. 194-203, DOI: 10.18517/ijaseit.9.1.5322

Journal

Skills_

Programming Matlab, Python

Languages English, French (basic), Spanish (mother tongue)

Awards_____

2015 **First place**, graduating class

Lima, Perú